Hello friends, my name is Abhishek Gul and
welcome to my channel Invest In Shore.
Friends, whenever a person goes out to search for a health
insurance, the first thing he does is
ask the people around him that which is the
best health insurance, then someone
tells him Star, someone tells him HDFC,
someone tells him Care, finally all the three
health insurance products
and in all this confusion, he finally
delays in buying his product,
so today in this video, to
remove that confusion, we will compare the products of not two, three or four but total
nine health insurance companies
in detail, in which we will
tell you about the features, will tell you
about their optional coverage, will tell you about the
USP of each product, will
tell you about the premium and how the premium slabs
change, will also tell you about
their network hospitals as well as the
loadings that come in their premium,
plus we will also
tell you what is the claim settlement ratio of each product
and which product you should
finally buy, so friends, this video is going to be
a bit long, so you all are
requested not to forward it and watch it
because if you have not seen this  If you watch this 15 to 20 minute
video properly,
your search for health insurance for the next 15 to 20 days will
end. You will finally be
able to decide which health insurance
product to buy. Before moving forward,
friends, I request all of you that if
you have found our channel for the first time, then please
subscribe to our channel so that you all keep getting
such great videos. And then
if you like the comparison, please
like and share because friends,
we work very hard to make such videos. So let's move ahead
and compare all the products. The
nine health
insurance products that we are going to compare
are
hdfc.com Apex Health Advantage Plus,
Supreme TA Medi Premier
Care, Cigna Pro Health Prime Plan and
Aditya Billa Platinum Enhance Plan. So let's
compare these nine health insurance companies in detail and see which
health insurance is the one that you can buy.
First of all, we will talk about sum insured.
Friends, if you look here, then the
minimum sum insured in all the companies is Rs 5 lakh.  The option of sum insured
is available and if we talk about maximum sum insured, then
in Bajaj you have been
given the option of taking sum insured up to Rs 5 crore,
whereas other health insurance companies are providing you the option of Rs 1
crore, Rs 2 crore and even Rs 3 crore.
Now let's talk about
entry age eligibility, then
in all the products a minimum entry age of 90 or 91 days has been given
and if I
talk about the maximum entry age, then
if you look here, in most of the companies
you have been given a maximum entry age of 65 years.
In some companies like Care,
Cigna and Aditya Billa, you have been given the
option of life long entry, that is,
you can enter this product whenever you want, there is no
type of limitation
given. Now let's talk about child age
maximum limit. If you are taking a family floater
policy, then
how long can your child remain in your policy? If
you look here, in all the companies the
maximum age limit is almost 25 years. Your Bajaj
My Health Care  You have been given an age limit of 30 years.
Now let's talk about
copayment, here no
type of copayment is given in all the products except
Accept for Star Ratio, in which if you
enter 61 or after that then you have to pay a
mandatory copayment of 10%. Now let's talk about
room rent and IC charges,
here again you are being provided actuals in all the companies.
In Star Assure, if you have a policy of lower sum insurance
then you get Accept for Sweet and
now you get all the categories. If you are
taking sum insurance of Rs 5 lakh then you have been given a
capping of 1% of sum insurance, whereas if
you go for high sum insurance then
Sweet room is also available to you. At Bajaj, the
company gives you multiple options
where if you want, you can take a shared room,
single private issue room,
deluxe room, sweet room,
you have to pay premium accordingly
and in Cigna and Aditya Billa
you  By default, you get a single private EC room,
but if you wish, you can convert
it into any room category by paying an extra premium.
Now let's talk about pre
and post hospital expenses, that is, the
expenses before hospitalization and after discharge. Almost all
companies are providing up to 60 days of pre-
hospitalization cover and up
to 180 days of post-hospitalization expense
cover. In Ta, friends, the company is
providing only 90 days of post-hospitalization expense cover. Friends, in Bajaj, the
company has given multiple options for fee and post,
where in case of pre-
hospitalization, you can increase it from 30 days to
180 days and in
case of post-hospital expenses, you can
increase it from 90 days to 240 days.
Now let's talk about cumulated bonus, that is,
if there is no claim in your policy, then the
company provides bonus after
renewal. If you look here,
almost all companies provide you  It provides up to 100% no
claim bonus but Nip
Rio 2.0 provides you 100% no lems
which increases up to a maximum of 500.
In this, another company has given an option
that is Titanium in which yours increases up to 1000%
by paying extra
premium. If you see there, it
refills the inclusion. So if you
see here, the company is providing
you unlimited distribution in all cases.
Same person gets
registration for the same illness and
partial registration is also available. Only if
you see, in Aditya Billa, you
get restoration only for unrelated illness and for your
road ambulance, if you
see here, all the companies are providing you actuals
except for II Ker
Ta and Aditya Bella. Now let's talk about road
ambulance, here again maximum coverage up to
₹5000000 is being given in all the companies.
Now let's talk about
domus hospitalization, that is, any
illness for which you are getting treatment from home due
to non-availability of room in the
hospital or due to the patient's condition not being good.
If you see here,
all the companies are providing you up to sum insurance coverage.
In some companies, there are some
specific diseases for which the company is
not providing you coverage in case of
domus hospitalization. If you
see here, there are some limits in Star Assure,
in ICICI Care, in Bajaj,
in Cigna and in Aditya Billa, there are some
diseases which the company is
not covering in domus hospitalization. Now let's
talk about day care treatment, that is,
any illness for which
hospitalization is not required as of today, like
kidney stone treatment or
cataract surgery, the company provides coverage for all these.
If you
see here, all the companies are providing up to sum insurance coverage.
Here, friends, if
you see, in Bajaj, the company is providing coverage for 399 procedures.
And
in Aditya Birla, you get coverage of 586 procedures,
in all other companies you get coverage of all day care treatment.
Now let's talk about organ
donors. In case an organ in your body
fails and if someone donates an organ to you, then the
company also provides the expenses for that. If you
see here, then all the companies are providing you coverage of up to sum
insured. Some
companies are providing you coverage of inpatient
and some companies are providing you coverage of harvesting of
organs. Now let's talk about
free health checkup. Every company
gives you free health checkup against
your policy based on your sum insured.
If you see here, then in almost all the
companies you
get free health checkup on cashless basis, for which you have to
go to their center and on a cashless
basis based on your sum insured, you
get free health checkup. In Aditya Birla,
friends, the company
provides you free health checkup on reimbursement basis,
for which you can make any  Get your health checkup done at Just Pathology and
submit the bills and reports to the company. The company will refund your
money. At Care Supreme, the
company has provided it as an optional coverage. Now,
talking about modern treatments,
almost all companies provide you with up to sum
assured coverage.
In Nip Rish 2.0, the company has
provided a cap of up to ₹1 lakh for robotic surgeries. Now,
talking about AYUSH treatments, here
again all companies provide you with up to sum assured
coverage.
At Star Assure, you get treatment for all types
of alternative treatments like Ayurveda,
Yoga, Unani Siddha, Homeopathy.
At Bajaj, you get coverage for only Ayurvedic and
Homeopathic treatments.
Next is non-consumable
items. If you look here,
hdfcfund.com, Cigna provide you with the option of deductible,
which you
can choose to reduce your premium.
However, other companies do not provide this.
Next is Compassion Travel. If you are
hospitalized in a city other than your own due to any illness or accidental injury and
come to a life-threatening situation, then the company provides travel expenses for your
immediate family member to come to you. So,
if you look here, Star Air,
IIC, and Bajaj are providing you coverage.
Next is Improvised Reproductive
Treatment. We can also call it IVF treatment.
Star Asher, Bajaj, and Cigna are
providing coverage for it. However,
it is optional in Cigna for which you have to pay an
extra premium. Other
health insurance companies are
not providing coverage for it. Now let's talk about
maternity coverage. Again, if you
look here, Star Asher
is providing you coverage for it. Bajaj and Cigna are
providing you coverage with the
different years of waiting. Other health
insurance companies are not providing maternity coverage.
Now let's talk about newborn
baby coverage. So, again, if you
look here,  So Star Ratio is providing newborn baby
coverage. In
case
you suffer from any of the critical illnesses listed by the company, the company provides
you a sum benefit.
Next is hospital cash benefit.
Again, here if you are hospitalized, the
company
provides you cash benefit apart from your normal claim.
Next is deducted option. As I
told you, if you choose this option,
your premium is reduced by a certain percentage,
but whatever
deductible you have chosen, if you get a claim in future,
you will have to pay that much percentage. The rest is
provided by the health insurance company. Next
is unlimited restore. In ADAC Optimal
Secure, the company provides only one time registration,
but if you pay % of premium
extra, your restoration
becomes unlimited. Next is personal
accident cover. If you choose this option, then in case
you
die due to accident or suffer permanent
disability, the company  Whatever
sum is there, it gives it to you. Now let's talk about the
optional coverage which is available in Starr.
In this the company has given only one optional
coverage and that is deductible, which again
if you choose then your premium gets
reduced but at the same time
whatever deductible amount you choose,
you will have to pay it yourself. In NIP YO 2.0
you have been given the option of deductible,
safeguard benefit has been given, if you
choose this option then basically the
company provides you three benefits,
first your non-medical items like gloves,
masks, PP kits are covered,
second if tomorrow you have a claim up to ₹ 1 lakh then
your no claim bonus which you are getting in Boor Plus does
not get affected,
third according to inflation the
company increases your insured every year which
is approximates is personal
accident cover, if you choose this then due
to accident if you die or  In case of
permanent disability,
whatever sum is insured is given to you.
In this also you are being
provided coverage of hospital cash benefit.
Now let us talk about
what optional coverage is available in Apex Health Advantage Plus. So,
two coverages are being given to you in this,
one is Claim Protector, if you choose it, then you start
getting coverage of non-medical items as well and the
second is Sum Insured Protector, if
you choose it,
your sum insured is increased every year on the basis of inflation, which
is
Approximate
Benefit, which is available in Care Supreme.
Here you get Claim Shield, this
Claim Shield is for non-medical items coverage.
If you choose it, then your non-
medical items also come under coverage.
Sum Insured Super: If you choose this option, then
apart from your normal No
Claim Bonus, which is 100%, the company separately
increases you up to Rs. 500, that is
If your policy is of Rs 10 lakh, then your normal
no claim bonus will become 20 times 10
and if you choose this, then you
get a separate no claim bonus of Rs 50 lakh.
Next is Annual Health Checkup: If you
choose this option, then all the
insured members can get free health checkup.
Next is Instant Cover: If
you have any disease like BP, Sugar before taking the policy
and you do
not want any waiting period for it, then if you choose this, then
after 30 days you start getting coverage for all these.
Next
is Reduction of PD: If you already have any
pre-existing disease like BP, Sugar
and you want to make its waiting period 3 years, 2 years, 1
year, then if you choose this option, then you
can reduce it by paying extra premium. Next is Care
OPD: If you choose this, then the
company also provides you OPD service on cashless basis.
Now let's talk about the
option coverage which it
provides, that is, if tomorrow  If you are
hospitalized, the company
provides you with a separate income benefit.
Next is Major Illness and Accident
Multiplier. If a person
suffers a major illness or a
major injury due to an accident, the
company increases his/her base sum assured.
Next is Global Cover. The company
also offers the option of global coverage.
Next is Voluntary Copayment. If you
wish, you can reduce your policy premium
by taking copayment. In this,
you will have to pay the particular copayment amount. The
rest is paid by the health insurance company
whenever you receive a claim. Now let's talk about the
optional coverage available with Cigna. The
first is the Any Room option. For example,
in this product, you get a single private AC room.
If you choose this option,
you can move into any room. Next is
Health Maintenance Benefit (OPD). If you
choose this, the company provides you with separate health
maintenance OPD coverage.
Next is Maternity and Newborn.
Baby Coverage: If you choose this option,
you get reimbursement for all the expenses related to maternity
and also for the
expenses of a new born baby.
Next is
Non-Medical Item Coverage: Again, if you choose this option, you get coverage for non-
medical items like gloves, masks, PP
kits.
Next is
Deducted: If you choose this,
your premium gets reduced by a certain percentage,
but in case of any claim,
you will have to pay that much.
In this also, the company is providing you Personal Accident Cover.
Next is
Cumulative Bonus: If you choose this option,
then apart from your normal No Claim
Bonus, the company gives you a separate No Claims cover.
Next is Critical Illness Coverage:
If you choose this option, then if you suffer
from any of the company's listed critical illnesses, then the
company provides you a
lump sum benefit. Next is
IVF Treatment: If you choose this option  If you are looking to undergo
IVF treatment, the
company provides coverage for that as well.
Now, let's talk about the optional
coverage available in the Aditya Billa plan. The
company offers you the option of Super Reload.
If you choose this option,
your restoration becomes unlimited times
and is triggered by the first claim.
Next is Surgery Cash. If you choose this
option, in case
you are hospitalized due to an accident or illness
and undergo surgery, the
company provides you cash benefit.
Next is Future Secure. If you
choose this option, the company
provides coverage for non-medical items. The
company
increases your sum insured every 5 to 6 years as per inflation
and does not impact your no-claim bonus.
Next is Cancer
Hospitalization Booster. If you choose this option,
the company doubles your sum
insured if the insured member is diagnosed with cancer. Next is
Vaccine Cover.  The company is
providing you coverage related to the vaccine.
Next is personal accident cover.
In this, if you face
death or permanent liability through an accident, then the
company provides you a claim.
Next is critical illness cover. If you
choose this option, then if you suffer from
any of the 20 critical illnesses listed by the company, then the
company provides you a lump sum benefit.
Next is international
coverage for 16 major critical illnesses. If you
choose this option, then if
you want to go for international treatment for any of the 16 major critical illnesses, then the
company provides coverage for that too.
Next is hospital cash benefit
apart from your normal benefit. The company
provides you a separate cash benefit.
Next is room type. If you choose this option,
then you can move from a single private AC room to any
room. So friends, in this way
we have covered the optional benefits. Now let's talk about the
waiting period and network
hospitals. If you look here,
In almost all the products, your
initial waiting period is 30 days only. Now let's
talk about waiting period for specific
illnesses or slow growing illnesses. If you
look here again,
you have been given a waiting period of 2 years in all the companies.
However, in Bajaj, the company has given optional coverage
in which you can extend the
waiting period for your specific illness to
one year by paying extra premium. Next is
waiting period for pre-assisting
diseases like BP, sugar. If you
look here, almost all the companies have
given a waiting period of 3 years.
In II, you get a waiting period of only 2 years.
In TA also, you get a
waiting period of 2 years. Whereas in Care,
you have been given a waiting period of 4 years.
Next is PD loading, that is, when
you are taking health insurance,
apart from your normal premium, the company
charges something extra. If you have any
disease like BP, sugar, then if
you look here, you will get extra premium in almost all the companies.  You have to pay
for your pre-existing disease except for
Star Care and Cigna. Now let's talk about the
PD reduction option, that is, if you do
not want to serve the waiting period for a pre-existing disease, then has the
company
given you the option to reduce it? If
you look here, it is given to you in N, it is given
in Care, it is given in Bajaj
and this option is given in Aditya Billa.
Now let's talk about network
hospitals. If you look here,
ADFC Star and Navap have more than 13000
network hospitals. Other health
insurance companies have approximately 8000 to
1122000 network hospitals.
Now let's talk about the premium. If I
look at the premium of Rs 10 lakh for two adults to two children, then if you look here,
and if you go to a higher city for
treatment, then also you do
not need to pay any payment, whereas
in your treatment base, if you live in Zone 3
or Tier 1 and
if you take the premium there, but you
go to Tier 1  If you are getting your treatment done then
you have to pay co-payment, so here
different health insurance companies
charge premium in different ways, so if
you see, here in III, Bajaj,
Cigna and Aditya Billa it is
treatment based, so in all these companies
if you are taking any product then you should
take zone one or tier one premium so that
you do not have to make any payment from your end in future.
Now let's talk about
how the company changes the premium, so here
if you see then every company
changes it slab wise, the normal slab is
one premium till 35, from 35 to 45
normally there is one premium, then
in the next five years the company changes the premium,
so here in almost all the companies
you have slab wise premium change,
in ADAC every year  The premium does change,
however, the premium that changes every year in ADAC
changes slightly,
which changes almost the same in 5 years as
a company charges you after 5 years.
So friends, in this way we have
covered the premium details as well as the
waiting period along with the network hospital.
Now let's talk
about the claim. Friends, the
data that we have extracted regarding the claim is basically from the
public disclosure on the company's website,
whatever data the company brings related to the
claim, we extract this data from it.
If you look here, the percentage of
claims settled in less than 30 days, Nipa
IIC and Care are performing better,
whereas Ta is a little behind. Now let's talk about the
percentage of claims received on
overall claim. So if you look here, then the
income rate means how much
premium the company is collecting and how much
portion of it is it giving towards the claim. So if
you look here, the
highest  The income ratio of ADFC is coming up,
which means if the company is collecting ₹1, then the
company is giving ₹83 towards its claim. On the other hand, if
you see, the lowest
income claim ratio is of Care Supreme, which
is 56, which means if the company is collecting ₹1, then it is
giving ₹6 towards the claim. Now let's
talk about claim settlement ratio,
here
hdfc0cpdccb
[Music]
ment means that tomorrow if any of your
claims comes which goes into rebus ment, then
you do
not need to send any physical document, you can sit at home and
submit your documents online to the company, the
company will give you your money. Next
is free health checkup again, this is on
reimbursement basis, for which
you do not need to go to their centre,
you can get your checkup done in any Yes Pathology,
submit the bills report to the company, the
company will give you your money. Next
is plus benefit, in this the company is your base  The
sum increases by 50%
up to a maximum of 100% and is irrespective of whether you have a
claim or not. Now let's talk about the
unique features available in STAR. It provides
IVF treatment, maternity
coverage, coverage for repatriation of motel remains, and the
highest
network hospitals. Now let's talk about the
unique features available in STAR.
In this, you get a lock-the-clock benefit,
which means
your premium does not change until you have a claim. Next
is Recharge Plus benefit. In this, basically, if
you have a claim tomorrow and once
your Recharge Plus is triggered, then
that lifetime benefit gets added to your base amount.
Next is Recharge Plus. In this,
basically, the company increases your base amount from time to time if
you opt for the
Titanium option. Now let's talk about the unique
features available in IC. First of all,
its premium is very low. Secondly, it
provides coverage for biometric surgery. Secondly, it provides
travel benefit coverage.  The
waiting period for PD is
less. Now let's talk about the unique features
available in Kay Supreme. Your
base sum can be increased up to 5x.
You are given the option of instant cover and
modification of PD.
And on top of this, its
premium is less compared to other health
insurance companies. Now let's talk about the
unique features available in Kay Supreme. In this,
you are given the option of global coverage.
Coverage of high-end diagnostic tests is being
provided on an OPD basis. This
means that if tomorrow you are
showing symptoms of any serious disease and the doctor does
something like MRI or CT scan,
but nothing is found in your body, then the
company will also cover that cost up to ₹5000000.
Next is OPD and dental
treatment. Here, the company
also provides coverage for OPD dental treatment
with the waiting period of 2 years. Next is the
lesser PD waiting period. If you have any
pre-aging disease, then its waiting
period is only 2 years. Now let's talk about it.
Bajaj's unique feature is maternity coverage. In this, the company is
providing you maternity coverage,
global coverage and is
also providing coverage for OPD expenses.
Now let's talk about the unique features
available in Sanaap. Here, the company is giving you a Cumet
Bonus Booster. So, apart
from your normal No. 10 Bonus, the company is separately
providing you a Booster Benefit,
Hospital Cash Benefit. You
can reduce your maternity waiting period. It is providing a Switch Off Benefit, in
which if you
inform the company that you are going
out of India for a month, then
your premium for that particular period is
reduced, which you get as a
discount in the renewal premium.
Now, let's talk about the unique feature
available in Aditya Birla. Here,
wide optional coverage is being provided. As
you saw, Aditya Birla is
providing multiple optional covers.
If you choose these, then your basic  The
policy becomes a fully featured policy.
It offers a 1-year recovery benefit, provides
coverage for obesity and mental illness, and on top of
that, the company is offering it at a lower premium.
So, friends, in this way, we've
covered everything for all the products. I hope
you liked the information. We've included
brochures for all the products
in the description link; you can browse
through them if you wish. Now, let's discuss which
product you should consider. Friends, each
product offers unique features. Just
as every individual is different, so is
every product.
Choose according to your requirements.
Some may need maternity coverage,
others may need a lower premium, or
others may want a good company with a good
claim settlement ratio.
Consider all these factors, and only then can
you get a good health insurance.
Now, I request you to
tell us in the comment section below
which health insurance product, considering all these factors, you think is the best.
You would like to get it for yourself, so I hope you
liked our small comparison and opinion. We
deal in products of all major health insurance companies,
so if you have any health
insurance requirement, you
can contact us on the number given below,
we will try to give you the best deal.
If you have any health insurance related
query, you can ask us in the comment box below,
we will try to answer your questions.
If you want to
know the comparison of any other product or want to get any
other product reviewed, then you can
ask us in the comment box below, we will try to
cover them in the upcoming videos. If you liked the video, then like,
share and subscribe.